# Sujeet Kc

Halifax, Canada

sujeetkc45@gmail.com

+1-9029893010

kcsujeet

in kcsujeet

kcsujeet.com.np

#### **Profile**

Dedicated and hardworking full stack developer with 3+ years experience in web development. Skilled in both F/E and B/E technologies. Well-versed in writing code to create systems that are reliable and userfriendly. Always on the look out for new learning opportunities and for growth as an individual.

## **Professional Experience**

09/2021 - present

Legalfit 🛮

Remote

Front End Developer

- Development and maintenance of in-house software solutions
- Involvement in decision making for new software integrations
- Code reviews and feedback for junior team members

02/2020 - 09/2021

**Tekvortex** 

Lalitpur, Nepal

Software Engineer

- Mentoring of new recruits
- Code review and feedback for team members
- Finding solution for production bugs
- Writing documentations for various new features that I worked

02/2019 - 02/2020

**TekVortex** 

Lalitpur, Nepal

Associate Software Engineer

- Carried out software maintenance for CloudChomp products. Developed fixes and introduced new functionalities to the web based products using Ruby on Rails, Angular and PostgreSQL.
- Refined database queries according to the changes in web
- Developed unit tests using RSpec to verify changes and improve quality.
- Conducted research to form an understanding of the best solutions, compiling pros and cons of systems and databases.
- Worked in Agile approach, attending Stand-ups and using JIRA to update tasks.
- Ensured deliverables adhered to in-house processes and strict regulatory requirements.

#### Skills

**Programming Languages** 

Javascript, Ruby, Python

**Data Management** 

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL

Frameworks & Libraries

Ruby on Rails, Express, Firebase, Django, Angular, Vue, React

**Tools and Principles** 

Docker, Rest-API, GraphQL, JWT, OAuth, RegEx

Education		
12/2021 – present	<b>Dalhousie University</b> Master of Computer Science	Halifax, Canada
2014 – 2018	IOE, Pulchowk Campus Bachelor in Computer Engineering Aggregate Score: 68.79 %	Lalitpur, Nepal
2012 – 2014	<b>Tulasi Boarding Higher Secondary School</b> <i>Higher Secondary</i> Aggregate Score: 81.40 %	Tulsipur, Nepal

## **Personal Projects**

12/2020 - present

#### MEN Auth

This is a Mongo, Express, Node API with JWT authentication. Features include:

- Token refreshing
- Token invalidation
- CSRF protection
- Password Recovery
- Persistent session

11/2020 - 12/2020

# React-Firebase Todo App 🛮

It is a simple todo app made with React on the front-end and Firebase on the backend. Features include:

- Authentication
- Authorization
- Image Upload

10/2020 - 10/2020

Hindi

## React portofolio 🛮

This is the first react app that I created. I learned the basic concepts of react while doing this project. Features include:

- Light/Dark theme
- Scroll Animations

## Languages

Nepali  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$  English  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$